往右传  往右传
On your right. On your right. On your right.
回防  回防  回防  加油伙计
Back, back, back, back, back. Come on, buddy.
好样的  丹  好样的
Yeah, Dan! Yeah!
漂亮  漂亮
Yea.! Yea.!
退守  退守  盯防边锋
Back, back, back, back, back. Watch the winger.!
你怎么了
You okay?
丹  丹  说话
Dan? Dan, talk to me.
丹  丹
Dan. Dan.
这儿需要医生
Get a doctor!
-嘿  -把门关上
- Hey.  - Close the door.
快把门关上
Close the door.
卡迪是不是在跟你玩躲猫猫呢啊
Is Cuddy down the hall counting to 50?
她知道我在这儿  在门诊
She knows I'm in here, in the clinic,
正像她指示的那样
as she commanded.
她只是不知道我没看病人
She just doesn't know I'm alone.
候诊室都人满为患了
Well, you've got a full waiting room.
-你还要无视他们多久  -我四点下班
- How long do you think you can ignore them?  - I'm off at 4:00.
你这样做就为了逃避5分钟的工作啊
You're doing this to avoid five minutes of work?
如果我出去看病
If I go out there,
我将面对一个流鼻涕的小朋友
I get assigned a kid with a runny nose.
也就是花30秒医好他的鼻子
That's 30 seconds looking at the nose,
再花25分钟和忧心忡忡的母亲聊天
25 minutes talking to a worried mom.
直到让她相信
who won't leave until she's sure
孩子得的不是脑膜炎或癌症才肯离开
it's not meningitis or a tumor.
是啊  瞎操心的家长真烦人啊
Yes. Concerned parents can be so annoying.
直接告诉卡迪你有重病患者
Just tell Cuddy you've got an urgent case.
需要提前结束门诊就完了
You had to leave early.
那可是在说谎
That would be lying.
说谎话不好是吧
And that would be wrong.
而且好在"轻重"是一个相对概念
But luckily the definition of"urgent" is fungible.
但是患者是绝对概念
Not the definition of"case" though.
你没有患者吗
You have no cases?
一个患者都没有吗
你精挑细选了一批精英级医生
You've got handpicked doctors-specialists-
为你工作  就让他们百无聊赖吗
working for you,and they're sitting on their hands?
卡梅隆在帮我回复邮件
Cameron's answering my mail.
真是相当充分的利用了时间
Oh, time well spent, I'm sure.
福曼和奇斯呢
Foreman and Chase?
做科研吧
Research?
一种儿童碘缺乏症  9个字母
Nine letters. Iodine deficiency in children.
呆小症
Cretinism.
下午4点零3分  豪斯医生签到下班
So, 4:03 p.m., Dr. House checks out.
请帮忙记录一下
Please write that down.
-豪斯医生吗  -抱歉  今天下班了
- Dr. House.  - Sorry. Done for the day.
会有很多其它医生给你看病
Plenty of docs here to take care of you.
但是咱们约好的
But we had an appointment.
很棒的试探  但是这是个免费门诊
Nice try, but this is a walk-in clinic,
也就是说没有预约制度
which means there are no appointments.
免费门诊  进来填表  就有医生给你看病
You walk in, sign the chart,and a doctor will see you.
只不过不是我
Just not me.
您的邮件上说你会给我们看病的
Your letter says that we'd see you.
-我不怎么写信  -你看
- Not a big letter writer.  - Here.
我的签名什么时候变得娘们儿了
When did my signature get so girlie?
-我可以解释  -看见这个G没有
- I can explain.  - See that "G"?
上边的怎么会写出一个圈圈来呢
See how it makes a big loop on top?
看起来根本不像我的字体  知道怎么想吗
Doesn't even look like my handwriting. Think I have something?
给一个像初中女生一样写G的人
What's the differential diagnosis for
应该下什么诊断呢[在暗示同性恋]
writing G's like a junior high school girl?
想通过正常渠道找你看病简直是不可能
It's impossible to get to you through normal channels.
电话  邮件  他们都试过了
They have called, e-mailed.
坚持不懈并不等于值得关注
Perseverance does not equal worthiness.
下次再想吸引我注意
Next time you want to get my attention,
你可以在穿着上来点儿猛料
wear something fun.
低腰牛仔裤挺性感
Low-rider jeans are hot.
十六岁男性病人
Sixteen-year-old male.
未知原因的产生重影和夜惊
Sudden onset of double vision and night terrors, with no apparent cause.
-孩子已经看过两位精神科专家  -夜惊
- The kid's been to two neurologists, and he  -Night terrors?
-像是恐怖怪兽里面的一样吗  -是的
- As in big scary monsters?  - Yes.
-你去哪  -看看这家人去
- Where are you going?  - To see the family.
你要去给患者做检查吗
You're going to examine a patient?
九成情况下  不用和患者谈话
Nine times out of 10,there's no reason to talk to a patient.
但是一个16岁的孩子夜惊
But night terrors in a 16-year-oldis a very good reason
是一个去和他家人聊一聊非常好的理由
to talk to this family.
干得好
Good work.
边缘良好
Margins are fine.
无破损
No lesions.
颜色不错
Color is good.
-夜惊有多久了  -3周
- How long have you been having night terrors?  - Three weeks.
他害怕去睡觉  已经累坏了  快挺不住了
He's afraid to go to bed.He's exhausted, can barely function.
这说明什么
What does that tell you?
什么都说明不了  看他眨眼睛挺好玩的
Nothing. It's just fun watching him blink.
尽可能多说出B开头的动物名称  开始
Name as many animals as you can that begin with the letter "B." Go.
-大象宝宝  -倒真是个不错的答案啊
- Baby elephant?  - Baby elephant is actually a good answer.
B是一个笨拙的字母[熊]
"B" is a bear of a letter.
这又说明什么呢
What does that tell you?
说明两个问题  神经系统正常
Proves two things: No neurological damage,
你儿子不可能当厨师了
and your son is never gonna be chief fry cook.
十多岁孩子夜惊只可能有两种原因
In teens, there are two likely causes of night terrors.
外伤造成的压力
Posttraumatic stress.
-最近在学校火拼了吗  -没有
- Any recent shoot-outs at your high school?  - No.
-那么戴夫  -是丹
- Well then, Dave  - Dan.
如果没有外伤
If there's no trauma,
那么另一个原因就是  性侵犯
the other cause is... sexual abuse.
有谁性骚扰你吗  老师
So who's molesting you? Teacher?
份外友好的邻居吗
Extra-friendly neighbor?
我想问你俩是帮凶吗
I'd ask if either of you were involved,
但是你们肯定不会承认的
but you'd deny it.
我们绝对不会伤害丹的
We would never do anything to hurt Dan.
我这边儿刚说完  那边儿就映证了
I say it here, it comes out there.
失去反应和性虐待有关
This lack of response is consistent with abuse.
从没有过这种事情好吗  我发誓
There's no one, okay? I- I swear.
有外伤  我在长曲棍球赛中头部受伤了
There was trauma. I got hit in the head during a lacrosse game.
你知道他头部受伤吗
Did you know that he got hit in the head?
他们从来没提过
They didn't mention it. No.
是啊  这点小事儿何必一提呢
Yeah. Why bother?
不对  不对  比赛之后
No, no. We took him to the E.R.
我们送他去急诊室了
After the game.
医生为他做了扫描  说他没事儿
He was scanned. They tested him. They said he was fine.
没有脑震荡  肯定是其它别的什么原因
No concussion. It's gotta be something else.
你吵着要我给你诊断  又质疑我的诊断
You hound me for my opinion, and then you question my diagnosis.
好吧  急诊室显然搞错了  孩子脑震荡了
Cool. E.R. obviously screwed up. Kid's got a concussion.
在被撞击前我看东西也会重影
I had double vision before I was hit.
很好  那样的话一切都不同了
Well, that changes everything.
你需要戴眼镜了
You need glasses.
那才是重影的原因
That's why you had double vision,
也是你被撞击的原因
which is why you got hit,
也是你脑震荡的原因
which is why you have a concussion,
和夜惊的原因
which is why you have night terrors.
你需要去看眼科专家  而且我不是
You need to see an ophthalmologist, which I am not.
你很喜欢这样子
You enjoyed that.
我给你送来了一个不错的病例
I brought a reasonable case to your attention,
而你当面解决掉  是想羞辱我吧
and you shoved it in my face just to humiliate me.
-你是独生女吧  -为什么这么说
- You're an only child, aren't you?  - Why would you say that?
因为你总是以自己为中心
Because everything is about you.
这个话题也许极富争议
This may seem incredibly controversial,
但是我认为性侵犯总是不好的
but I think sexual abuse is bad.
我只是想确定
I just wanted to make sure
他不是被他爸爸或者妈妈侵犯了
he wasn't being diddled by Daddy- or Mommy.
其它的部分只能算作是意外收获了
Anything else is just a bonus.
-我不是独生女  -有意思
- I'm not an only child.  - Interesting.
-什么  -别动
- What?  - Don't move.
我是不是让你觉得很无聊呢
Did I bore you in there?
什么  没有  真没有
What? Uh, no. Not- Not really.
你累吗
Are you tired?
-时而  -他一点儿觉没睡  当然疲劳了
- Sometimes.  - He never sleeps. Of course he's tired.
现在  此时此刻
Right now. At this moment.
-你累吗  -不 不累
- Are you tired?  - No. No.
那让你腿部抽动  你感觉到了吗
That twitch in your leg. Did you feel that?
-不疼吗  -他的腿抽搐  我不明白这
- Didn't hurt.  - His leg twitched. I don't see what-
这是种叫做肌阵挛的现象
It's called a myoclonic jerk.
很常见  经常发生在睡眠时候
It's very common when you're falling asleep.
呼吸率下降
Respiration rate falls,
大脑以为身体在衰竭而作出的条件反射
and the brain sometimes interprets this as the body dying,
释放出醒来的讯号
so it sends a pulse to wake it up.
-那又怎样  -所以他睡不着觉
- So?  - So, he's not asleep.
一直醒着
He's awake.
收他住院
Admit him.
我认得那个圈圈G
I recognize that loopy "G. '"
那么  混蛋是怎么说的
So, what does the jerk tell us?
没什么好消息  大脑在丧失对身体的控制
Nothing good. The brain's losing control of the body.
不能控制眼睛聚焦
Can't order the eyes to focus,
也不能控制正常的睡眠模式以及肌肉
regulate sleep patterns or control muscles.
不是运动功能紊乱就是脑功能衰竭
A movement disorder or a degenerative brain disease.
不管是哪种病
Either way,
这孩子都将要穿着尿布
this kid's gonna be picking up his diploma in diapers
坐着轮椅去领毕业证书了
and a wheelchair.
可能没那么严重  或许只是感染了
Maybe not that bad. Could be an infection.
一厢情愿  没有发烧  也没有白细胞增长
You wish. No fever, no white count.
有人认为这个鉴别诊断可能会有问题吗
Anyone think this differential diagnosis might be compromised
因为我们没有病人准确的家庭患病史
because we don't have an accurate family history?
我拿到了准确的家庭患病史
I took an accurate family history.
你甚至没见到准确的家庭
You didn't even take an accurate family.
-他父亲不是生父  -为什么这么说
- His father's not his father.  - Why would you say that?
大约有百分之三十的父亲
Thirty percent of all dads
不知道自己养了别人的孩子
don't realize they're raising someone else's kid.
错误的父子关系大概只有一成左右
False paternity's more like 10%.
妈妈更喜欢这种说法
That's what our moms would like us to believe.
有什么关系呢
Who cares?
如果是从他父母那儿遗传过来的
If he got it from his parents,
父母应该都已经死掉了
they'd both be dead.
我们可以继续这个鉴别诊断了吗
Can we get on with the differential diagnosis?
50块钱赌我是对的
Fifty bucks says I'm right.
-我一定赢你  -说到你痛处了吗
- I'll take your money.  - Hit a nerve?
别担心  我确定抚养你长大的是你亲生父亲
Don't worry. I'm sure the guy who tucked you in was your daddy.
加注到100块
Make it a hundred.
16岁得脑白质病的想法怎么样
What about leukoencephalopathy in a 16-year-old?
不一定非得是重病
It doesn't necessarily have to be that bad.
如果不考虑夜惊  可能是一种系统疾病
If we exclude the night terrors, it could be something systemic.
他的肝脏  肾脏
His liver, kidneys.
-除了大脑意外的器官  -好样的
- Something outside the brain.  - Yes.
排除所有的症状  你的工作就轻松了
Feel free to exclude any symptom if it makes your job easier.
夜惊可能是杜撰出来的症状
Night terrors were anecdotaly.
他可能是做了一个噩梦而已
He could've had a bad dream.
不对  他的家长说在夜惊的时候他意识清醒
No Parents said he was conscious during
之后就什么都不记得了
and didn't remember anything afterwards.
-那正是夜惊  -家长说的吗
- That's a night terror.  - Parents said?
说的好
That's a good point.
在我们判决这个孩子之前
Before we condemn this kid,
或许我们首先应该认同一下
maybe we should entertain
奇斯医生的怀疑精神
Dr. Chase's skepticism.
我想要一个份详细的睡眠记录
I want a detailed polysomnograph.
如果他真的夜惊
If he's having night terrors,
我要亲眼所见
I want to see them.
通常夜惊时我不会乱动的
I usually don't move during night terrors.
不是因为那个把你捆起来的
I'm not restraining you for them.
脑电图显示了你脑中的异常情况
E.E.G. revealed abnormalities in your brain-
导致你的脚趾神经受损
caused nerve damage in your toes.
你要做什么
What are you doing?
-修好它  -我能和我爸妈谈谈吗
- Fixing it.  - Can I talk to my parents?
他们已经同意了
Oh, they know all about this.
我特别想见见他们
I'd really like to see them.
求你了  我特别希望他们能在这儿
Please. I'd really like them here.
会很疼的  丹
This is gonna hurt, Dan.
哦  天啊
Oh. Oh, God.
那是夜惊的症状
That's a night terror.
我们做了CT透视
We did a C. T.,
核磁共振  全部血细胞计数
M.R.I., C.B.C.,
血液电解质测试  还有胸部X光透视
CHEM-7 and chest X-ray.
所有这些测试结果显示正常
All the tests came back normal.
无法解释他的症状
There's nothing to explain his symptoms.
好吧  那咱们只能假设出问题了
Okay, but let's pretend there's something and go from there.
谁能看出核磁共振图像上有什么异常之处
Who sees something on this M.R.I.?
白质没有损伤  也没有结构异常
No lesions in the white matter. No structural abnormalities.
没有无压迫性肿块
No space-occupying tumors.
他才16岁  大脑未发育完全
He's 16, so he should have an absolutely pristine brain.
最小的异常都有问题
The smallest thing is abnormal.
脑膜增生
Meningeal enhancement.
-我认为是病毒性脑膜炎  -很好
- My bet is viral meningitis. - Excellent.
你们看见人家怎么做的了吗
Do you see what he did there?
根据一点证明是神经问题的小线索
Took a small clue that there's a neurological problem
进行大胆地猜想
and wasn't afraid to run with it.
核磁共振没有显示脑膜炎的症状
There's no evidence of meningitis on that M.R.I.
没错  是没有  他完全说错了
No, there's not. He's completely wrong.
那你说的线索是哪个
Then what clue are you talking about?
他知道我从核磁共振上看出了些问题
He knew that I saw something on the M.R.I.,
所以他觉得一定是有问题  于是就猜了猜
so he figured there must be something there and took a guess.
-聪明  反被聪明误  -那你发现了什么
- Clever, but also pathetic.  - So what did you find?
仔细看看胼胝体
Take a close look at the corpus callosum.
-没问题啊  -咱们看的是同一个东西吗
- Looks okay.  - Are we all looking at the same thing?
两亿个脑半球之间的神经元
Two hundred million interhemispheric nerve fibers.
连接左右脑的华盛顿桥
The George Washington Bridge between the left and right side of the brain.
很精巧的
It's subtle.
胼胝体有些弯曲  就在那
There's some bowing. There.
-向上拱起  -你是猜的吗
- An upward arch. - Are you guessing?
是
Yes.
-很遗憾  猜对了  -他可能只是动了一下
- Too bad. You're right. - He probably just moved.
整个核磁共振检查中没人能保持完全静止
Nobody stays perfectly still for the entire M.R.I.
对  估计他躺得不耐烦了然后把自己
Yeah. Probably got restless and shifted
一侧的脑半球移到了个更舒服的位置
one hemisphere of his brain to a more comfortable position.
有东西压住了胼胝体
Something is pushing on it.
如果有弯曲的话  可能是肿瘤
If there was bowing, could be a tumor.
你在核磁共振上看见肿瘤了吗
Do you see a tumor on this M.R.I.?
没有  可我也没看见弯曲
No, but I don't see any bowing either.
没有肿瘤  只是阻塞导致颅内压力
There's no tumor. Just a blockage causing pressure
然后出现症状
causing symptoms.
今天是夜惊  明天就是眼睛出血
Today, night terrors. Tomorrow, he's bleeding out of his eyes.
给他做一个放射核甘脑池显像图
Get him a radionucleotide cisternogram.
保证你们会看到阻塞
I guarantee you'll see a blockage.
没事的
Okay.
放松
Easy.
乖  抓住我的手
Okay. Squeeze my hand.
没事的  抓紧
All right. Squeeze hard.
没事的
All right.
我在注射一种以放射性同位素
Now I'm injecting a material that's
为标记的物质
tagged with a radioisotope.
它会进入你的脊椎  流入大脑
It's gonna enter your spine and travel up to your brain.
它会让你思维变得深沉
It'll make you able to think deep thoughts,
每小时跑100米
run a hundred miles an hour.
放松
Easy.
他们眼睛的颜色不同  不过眼睛里那个斑点
Their eyes aren't the same color, but that fleck in the eyes-
他们不是亲生父子的几率有十分之一
That's maybe a one-in-10 chance if they're not related?
没戏  豪斯才不会因为这点理论就认输
No. House isn't gonna pay you based on that.
怎么才能让他们做个基因测试
Any excuse we can give the folks to justify a D.N.A. test?
我们可以说他得了亨丁顿氏舞蹈症
We could tell them he's got Huntington's-
全家人都要测试  不然就有生命危险
whole family should be tested or they'll all die.
嗨
Hey.
确实有很多阻塞
There's a lot of blockage.
我已经安排他进行手术了
I've scheduled him for surgery.
我们会将分流通管放入其中一个脑室
We're gonna put a shunt into one of the ventricles
使脑脊液流出
to give the cerebrospinal fluid an out.
消除了颅内压力  一切恢复正常
No more pressure, everything goes back to normal.
你们当他的医生  他真是三生有幸
He's lucky to have you as his doctors.
不喝配方奶  只喝健康自然的母乳
No formula. Just Mommy's healthy, natural breast milk.
美味
Yummy.
一夜之间她的脸就肿成这样了
Her whole face just got swollen like this overnight.
没有发烧
No fever.
腺体正常  她没有接种疫苗
Glands normal. Missing her vaccination dates.
我不会让她接种疫苗的
We're not vaccinating.
觉得疫苗没用是吗
Think they don't work?
我觉得是某些国际制药公司
I think some multinational pharmaceutical company
想让我以为疫苗有用
wants me to think they work-
好让他们赚钱
pad their bottom line.
-可以吗  -当然
- May I? - Sure.
全天然  不含化工染料  真是好做的生意
Yeah. All-natural, no dyes is a good business.
全天然儿童玩具
All-natural children's toys.
玩具公司  他们不会随便涨价
Toy companies- they don't arbitrarily mark up their frogs.
也不会在研究和开发的花销上做文章
They don't lie about how much they spend on research and development.
一个玩具公司  最糟的情况不过是
The worst that a toy company
因为做了个无聊的青蛙而被人指控罢了
could be accused of is making a really boring frog.
知道另一个很好做的生意是什么吗
You know another really good business?
小巧袖珍的婴儿棺材
Teeny, tiny baby coffins.
可以刷上青蛙绿的漆
You can get 'em in frog green,
消防车红色也行  真的
fire-engine red- really.
母乳里的抗体只能保护小孩6个月
The antibodies in yummy Mummy only protect the kid for six months,
所以这些公司才觉得他们能从你那捞一笔
which is why these companies think they can gouge you.
他们觉得
They think
为了让自己孩子活下去  你不惜付出一切
that you'll spend whatever they ask to keep your kid alive.
想改变现状吗  证明他们错了
Want to change things? Prove 'em wrong.
数百对父母跟你一样  决定宁愿
Few hundred parents like you decide they'd rather
让自己的孩子死掉
let their kid die
也不想掏那40块的疫苗钱
than cough up 40 bucks for a vaccination,
相信我  疫苗的价钱一定飞降
believe me, prices will drop really fast.
她到底得了什么病
Tell me what she has.
感冒
A cold.
出问题了
There's a problem.
-手术并发症吗  -手术很顺利  他在康复中
- Complications in surgery? - Surgery went fine.He's in recovery.
不过我们取了一瓶脑脊液  做了测试
But we took a vial of C.S.F. And tested it.
是嘛
Really?
结果显示弯曲并不是病因  是症状
Turns out the bowing wasn't the cause of his problems. It was a symptom.
寡克隆带弯曲
Oligoclonal bands
而且脊髓腔内免疫球蛋白G数量增加
and increased intrathecal IgG.
意味着是多发性硬化症
Which means multiple sclerosis.
还有为什么你们三个一起来通知我
And the reason it takes three of you to tell me this?
因为在多发性硬化症问题上我们意见不合
Because we're having a disagreement about whether or not it is M.S.
核磁共振并没有显示病灶
No lesions on the M.R.I.
还太早  他才患病2周左右
It's early. He's had the disease for maybe two weeks.
麦克唐纳诊断标准要求用六个月来确诊
McDonald criteria requires six months to make a definitive diagnosis.
谁在乎麦克皮尔森
Who cares about MacPhearson?
-我听说他虐待小猫  -是麦克唐纳
- I hear he tortured kittens. - McDonald.
噢  麦克唐纳  超赞的医生  爱惜小猫
Oh, McDonald. Wonderful doctor, loved kittens.
视觉诱发电位检查显示出大脑运转减速
The V.E.P. indicates slowing of the brain.
没有病灶  我们不能确定
Without the lesions, we can't be sure.
如果是的话
Well, if it is,
三周内从0升到60
it's gone from zero to 60 in three weeks,
说明是急性进展型多发性硬化症
which would indicate rapidly progressive M.S.
不是那个病患只需坐轮椅还能拿着气球
Not the fun M.S. with the balloons and
坐自行车出游的温和的多发性硬化症
the bike rides for cripples in wheelchairs.
-我们应该等到  -现在开始进行治疗
- We should wait until- - Start treating him now,
说不定他还能多活个5年
maybe he can walk for another couple of years,
2年内还能正常行走
maybe live for another five.
去通知家属  我要回家了
Break it to the family. I'm going home.
确诊的话需要几个月的时间
It'll take months for a definitive diagnosis.
那我会怎么样
What'll happen to me?
多发性硬化症是种极其多变的疾病
M.S. is an incredibly variable disease.
即使确诊了
If it is M.S.,
我们也不能百分百肯定
and we're not a hundred percent sure.
你觉得会出现什么症状
What do you think is gonna happen?
有一些治疗方案可以控制病发
There are some medications to manage the symptoms,
不过随着病情恶化  问题会逐渐严重
but as the disease progresses, the problems will become more severe.
排泄功能障碍
Bowel and bladder dysfunction,
失去认知能力  疼痛
loss of cognitive function, pain-
所以会很疼了
So it's gonna hurt?
大脑就像一团电线
The brain's like a big jumble of wires.
多发性硬化症使之失去绝缘层  神经死亡
M.S. strips them of the insulation, and the nerves die.
大脑认知为疼痛
Brain interprets it as pain.
疗程开始时
But by starting treatment,
我们会尽量避免这种情况发生
we're gonna prevent that for as long as possible.
我们在咨询一些专家
We're looking into a couple of specialists,
在一切准备就绪之前
and until we get you squared away,
你留在这里  好吗
you'll stay here, okay?
保安检查了医院所有外围监控录像
Security checked the videotapes from all perimeter cameras.
-他一定还在医院里面  -奇斯呢
- He's still gotta be in the hospital. - Where's Chase?
-在主层  -你去食堂和董事办公区方向找
- Main floor. - Okay. You take the cafeteria and administration.
我去研究部门那边找然后我会和你汇合
I'll hit the research annex and work my way back to you.
丹
Dan?
我不在家  请留言
I'm not here. Leave a message.
卡迪医生  行头不错
Dr.Cuddy. Great outfit.
你怎么回来了  有病人吗
What are you doing back here? Patient?
不是  是妓女
No. Hooker.
本来要去我家结果来我办公室了
Went to my office instead of my home.
豪斯医生
Dr.House.
-丹不见了  -我知道  你在留言里说了
- Dan's missing. - Yeah. I got that part from the message.
你说这儿急需我帮忙
You said I was needed immediately.
刚做完腰椎穿刺他不该走动的
He shouldn't move after a lumbar puncture.
是啊  他会有严重头疼症状
I agree. He's gonna have a very nasty headache.
如果明早会诊  我持相同观点
That would also be my opinion if consulted tomorrow morning.
我们想通知你
We wanted to keep you informed.
他听到了一些很不乐观的消息
He heard some pretty heavy news.
这又不是刚会走的小孩在百货公司乱逛
This is not a toddler wandering around a department store.
他都16了  你们会找到他的
He's 16. You'll find him.
我要回家了
I'm going home.
所以你说"有需要尽管给我打电话"
So when you say, "Call me if you need anything,"
意思就是不要打吗
you mean don't call?
不是  我是说我能帮上忙的话再打给我
No, I mean call me if I could do something.
我不擅长搜索救援组的工作
I'm bad at search parties, and I'm bad at sitting around
也不擅长干坐在这看着别人慌慌张张的
looking nervous, doing nothing.
那他父母呢  要打电话通知他们吗
What about his parents? Should we call them?
怎么  你觉得他们把他藏起来了
Why? Do you think they're hiding him?
找人去屋顶看看
Make sure someone checks the roof.
有些清洁工把门撑着留条缝好方便偷抽烟
Some of the orderlies keep the door propped open so they can grab a smoke.
丹  你没事吧
Dan. You okay?
有实验性疗程  正在进行的研究
There are experimental treatments. Ongoing research.
也许一两年之后会有所突破
Who knows what they'll discover in a year or two.
这就是我掉球的地方
This is where I dropped the ball.
丹  我们是站在医院的屋顶上
Dan, we're standing on the roof of the hospital.
丹
Dan.
丹  你不是在球场上
Dan, you're not on the field.
-他不知道自己在哪  -丹
- He doesn't know where he is. - Dan.
福曼
Foreman.
丹
Dan.
-丹  -丹  不要
- Dan? - Dan, no!
福曼医生
Dr.Foreman.
看来你们找到那孩子了
I assume you found the kid.
-他差点从屋顶掉下去  -想自杀吗
- He almost walked off the roof. - Suicidal?
不是  他以为在曲棍球场呢
No, he thought he was on his lacrosse field.
听着  我正要回家  冲凉  换衣服
Look, I was gonna run home, shower, change-
-神志清醒吗  -对
- Conscious? - Yeah.
你是怎么劝他下来的
How'd you talk him down?
其实  奇斯抱住了他
Actually, Chase tackled him.
怎么不是你呢
How come you didn't do it?
是呀  我是黑人  但他更近些
Right. Well, I am black, but he was closer.
来吧  和我一起上去
Come on. You can ride up with me.
他们知道儿子差点坠楼了吗
Anybody tell the family that their boy almost stepped off a roof?
一定给吓坏了
They must be thrilled.
他们没有起诉  我看是因为奇斯请求
They're not suing, but I think only because Chase asked-
为何总以为我在挖苦
Why does everybody always think I'm being sarcastic?
好消息  不是多发性硬化
This is great news. He doesn't have M.S.
父母应该很高兴  至少母亲是
Parents should be thrilled. The mom anyway.
当然  父亲可能还不知道
Of course, the dad probably doesn't know-
为什么不是多发性硬化
Why doesn't he have M.S.?
因为他在屋顶  幻觉在曲棍球场
He was on the roof, thinking he was on a lacrosse field.
神志清醒  所以不是夜惊
Conscious, and therefore not a night terror.
-你来点吗  -对  行
- You want some of this? - Yeah, sure.
他当时处在急性精神混乱状态
He was in an acute confusional state,
和多发性硬化等神经髓鞘剥落类疾病不符
which doesn't fit with a demyelinating disease like M.S.
-脑脊液寡克隆区带  -是存在的
- Oligoclonal bands - Were real.
不过  反映的不是多发性硬化
They just mean something
而是其它原因
other than M.S.
那么  是什么呢
So, what are they telling us?
-免疫系统正常  -对
- That the immune system is working? - Right.
他脑部有感染
He has an infection in his brain.
会不会和性有关[来做爱吧]
What about sex?
会很复杂的  我们是同事
Well, it might get complicated. I mean, we work together.
而且我又有点老  不过或许正对你胃口
I'm older, certainly, but maybe you like that.
我是说可能是神经性梅毒
I meant maybe he has neurosyphilis.
欲盖弥彰
Huh. Nice cover.
对不住  梅毒快速血浆反应素是阴性
Sorry. R.P.R. Was negative.
我们不需要定性检测来确诊
We don't need a definitive test to confirm.
对  也不需要结果来确诊多发性硬化
Sure. Didn't need one to confirm M.S.
那就等你测完1400种病毒做浓度测试之后
Okay. Let's wait for you to run titers on 1,400 viruses
这孩子的脑子也差不多了
while this kid's brain turns to mush.
事实是  他不是多发性硬化症
So the fact that he doesn't have M.S.,
这个  其实算不上好消息
it's- it's really not good news after all.
如果是神经性梅毒的话  就算个好消息
Well, it is if it's neurosyphilis.
梅毒检测的假阴性率是30%
The likelihood of a false negative on an R.P.R. Test: 30%.
16岁少年做爱的概率大概是120%
Likelihood of a 16-year-old having sex: Roughly 120%.
我会开始青霉素静脉滴注
I'll start him on I.V. Penicillin.
我们等不了
We're not gonna wait for that.
最有效给药途径是经脊柱注射进脑部
The most effective way to deliver the drug is right into his brain via the spine.
不能这么做  在如大脑一样的狭小空间
We can't. In a cramped space like the brain,
青霉素类高容积药物导致的颅内压增高
increased intracranial pressure from a high-volume drug like penicillin
可能会使脑干破裂
could herniate his brain stem.
那会杀了他的
It'd kill him.
正常的神经科医生都不会这么建议的
No neurologist in his right mind would recommend that.
举手投票  谁认为我不正常
Show of hands. Who thinks I'm not in my right mind?
谁认为我连这点神经学基本理论都不懂
And who thinks I forget this fairly basic neurological fact?
谁认为还有其它办法
Who thinks there's a third option?
很好  是什么
Very good. What's the third choice?
不知道  你只是问是否觉得有
No idea. You just asked if I thought there was one.
病人脑部有分流器  脑压不会增高
The patient has a shunt in his brain. There'll be no increased pressure.
我们想用多少青霉素都没有问题
We can put as much penicillin into his body as we want.
好极了  腰椎穿刺注射
Excellent. Inject him through a lumbar puncture.
我们中的一个会在接下来的两周内
One of us is gonna do this to you twice a day
每天给你注射两次
for the next two weeks.
我准备好了  开始吧
I'm ready. Go.
如果没有过性生活  他会感染上梅毒吗
He could get syphilis... even if he's not sexually active?
的确不太寻常  不过还是可能的
Well, it's- it's unusual, but it's possible.
好  放松
Okay. Relax.
感染了  有个挺大的口子
It's infected, with a really big hole,
象是你敲了个钉子进去  释放压力
like you stuck a nail in it to relieve the pressure.
-我不会那么做  -尽管伤口不规则
- I wouldn't do that. - Although the wound is irregular.
不是圆柱形的  像是三角形的
It's not cylindrical. It's shaped like a triangle.
那么就不是钉子
So, not a nail.
-餐刀吗  -我老婆的指甲挫
- Steak knife? - Wife's nail file.
指甲挫
Nail file.
疼痛会让你做蠢事
Yeah. Pain will make you do stupid things.
-来点放松一下吗  -好
- Something to take the edge off? - Yeah.
干杯
Cheers.
你家人在普林斯顿吗
So, you have family here in Princeton?
-没有  -因为工作吗
- No. - Here on work?
-不是  为什么你  -你的阴茎疼吗
- No. Why are you - Does your penis hurt?
不疼  干嘛  应该疼的吗
No. What? Should it?
没有  就是想问个不该问的问题
No. Just thought I'd toss you a really inappropriate question.
你的律师会很喜欢
Your lawyer's gonna love it.
我为什么要告你  我需要你治好我
Why would I want to sue you? I want you to treat me.
-你来自新泽西  梅普尔伍德  -对
- You're from Maplewood, New Jersey, right? - Yeah.
那么  为什么驱车70英里
Now, why would you drive 70 miles...
就为了治疗一个9岁小孩都能诊断的症状
to get treatment for a condition that a nine-year-old could diagnose?
流脓了  是个提示
It's the free-flowing pus that's the tip-off.
-我在城里  -不为家人  也不为工作
- I was in town. - Not for family. Not for work.
你驱车70英里  来到免费门诊
You drove 70 miles to a walk-in clinic.
沿途错过两家医院
You passed two hospitals on the road.
要么你对那些医院有看法
Now, either you've got a problem with those hospitals,
要么他们对你有看法
or they have a problem with you.
我猜你已把梅普尔伍德一半的医生给告了
My guess is you've sued half the doctors in Maplewood,
剩下的医生拒绝给你帮助
and the rest are now refusing to help you.
讽刺  不是吗  像那个起诉狼的男孩
It's ironic, isn't it? Sort of like the boy who sued wolf.
知道吗  我打赌我们有个医生叫'狼'
You know, I bet we have a doctor here named Wolf.
该多完美啊
How perfect would that be?
-我现在传呼他  -多谢了
- I'm gonna page him. - Okay. You know what? Thank you.
我会找到医生来处理这个的
I'm gonna find a doctor to take care of this.
我没说我不治你
I didn't say I wouldn't treat you.
我们会引流清理膝部
We'll drain your knee,
做些实验室检查  把你治好
run some lab work. Fix you up.
你为什么这么做
Why would you do that?
我以人为本呗
I'm a people person.
你真的给他治疗了吗
You actually treated him?
我只知道他起诉了几个医生
All I know is he sued some doctors.
我怎么知道他们不是活该自找的
Who am I to assume they didn't have it coming to them?
最最可爱的小网球服
The cutest little tennis outfit.
我还以为我要心脏病发了
My God, I thought I was gonna have a heart attack.
天  没看到你  太尴尬了
Oh, my. Didn't see you there. That is so embarrassing.
你的应召女郎怎么样
How's your hooker doing?
多谢关心  滑稽的故事
Sweet of you to ask. Funny story.
她要当医院领导了  但讨厌给别人找茬
She was gonna be hospital administrator, but just hated having to screw people like that.
我听说你在屋顶找到她的
Heard you found her on the roof.
你耳朵还真灵
You have very acute hearing
通知父母了吗
You notify the parents?
适当的时候  当然会
In due course, of course.
是否还有个关于父亲是否生父的打赌呢
And is there a paternity bet on the father of the patient?
听着不想我的为人
Doesn't sound like me.
就是你  但不代表你有罪
Well, it does, actually, but doesn't mean you're guilty.
-你这么想  -我看在大厅看到了他的父母
- You think?  -I saw the parents in the lobby.
聪明人显然压父亲
Smart money's obviously on the father.
我的人认识能帮你下50元注的人
My guy knows a guy who can get you in for 50 bucks.
行  告诉你的人  要是我赢了
Fine. Tell your guy, if I win,
你就得打领带去参加研讨会
you attend the faculty symposium, and you wear a tie.
要是我赢了  一周不干门诊
And if I win, no clinic hours for a week.
我的人会给你的人打电话的
My guy will call your guy.
她对她的工作很在行
She's very good at her job.
治疗应该很快会见效
The treatments should start helping soon.
如果你觉得集中注意力和记东西开始容易了
Let us know if it gets easier to focus on things,
就告诉我们
remember stuff.
丹  卡梅隆医生的项链很漂亮  不是吗
Hey, Dan. Isn't Dr. Cameron's necklace a beauty?
我想是产于南美的
Something South American, I think.
是  危地马拉的
Yeah. Guatemalan.
是条很酷的项链
It's a cool necklace.
-多谢  -这孩子很痛
- Thank you so much. - The kid's in pain.
-不要抵抗  任其发展  -不
- Don't fight it. Just let it happen. - No.
-两天内你会没命  -不什么
- You'll be dead in two days. - No what?
-我看就一天  -丹  你还好吗
- I give it a day. - Dan? You okay?
丹
Dan?
-夜惊  -他会在坟墓里腐烂
- Night terrors. - Decomposition once he's in the grave.
-和你父母告别吧  -他在幻听
- Say good-bye to your mother and father. - He's hearing voices.
你快死了  结束了  丹
You're dying. It's all over, Dan.
你快死了  快死了  死了
You're dying. Dying. Dead.!
立即静脉推注2毫克安定文
Push two milligrams I.V. Ativan, stat.
-都结束了  -加油  丹
- It's all over. - Come on, Dan.
从我脑袋里滚出去
Get out of my head!
幻听表示脑部功能进一步退化
Auditory hallucination shows further brain degeneration.
青霉素无效
Penicillin's not working.
要么青霉素是次品要么就是我们诊断错误
So either it's a bad batch of penicillin, or our diagnosis is wrong.
回到原点
Square one.
午夜
Midnite.
肝功能  尿素氮  肌氨酸酐  正常
L.F. T.'s, B.U.N. And creatinine are all normal.
不是糖尿病  没有阴离子隙
Diabetes is out, and no gap.
不是代谢性疾病
There goes metabolic.
磁共振血管造影结果排除血管炎
M.R.A. Rules out vasculitis.
L  炎症排除
"L" for inflammation.
太年轻  不可能是退行性疾病
Too young for anything degenerative.
D  排除
"D," see ya.
-N是肿瘤  -核磁共振成像没有异常
- "N" for neoplastic. - M.R.I. Was clean.
-I是炎症  -已经排除了
- "I" for inflammation. - We already did that.
就知道这一个I  够笨的
Stupid to have two I's in one mnemonic.
-还有呢  -感染
- What's the other one? - Infection.
寡克隆条带一定代表了什么
Oligoclonal bands still have to mean something.
可是没发烧
But no fevers.
白细胞数上升  仍在正常范围
White count's elevated, but within range.
不可能的我们都查了  都是阴性
We've tested for anything remotely possible. Everything's negative.
断层扫描排除硬膜下的
C.T. Scan rules out subdural.
损伤  后面还有更多
Trauma. Later much.
你们知道问题所在吗
You know the problem?
'午夜'的拼写是有个G和一个H的
"Midnight'"is actually spelled with a "G'"and an "H. '"
如果我们可以弄清楚他们代表什么
If we could just figure out what those letters stand for.
一个不正常的大脑  在寻开心
It's a sick brain, having fun,
折磨他  和他说话
torturing him, talking to him.
吓他个半死
Scaring the hell out of him.
做脑电图  左右眼眼动电图
Get him an E.E.G., left and right E.O.G.,
食道扩音器
esophageal microphones.
如果它要说话  我们就来听听
If this thing wants to talk, let's listen.
我们忽略了什么  搞砸了
We're missing something. This is screwed-up.
所以你就有了大脑和病毒对话的主意吗
That's why you came up with the brain talking to the virus thing?
我恐慌了  行吗
I panicked, okay?
听着很酷  他们吃这套
Sounded cool though. They bought it.
倒霉
Oh, crap.
我不喜欢见病人的另一个原因
Another reason I don't like meeting patients.
他们要是不认识你  就不会冲你吼
If they don't know what you look like, they can't yell at you.
现在开始
Here we go.
你怎么能安然坐在这里
How can you just sit there?
如果我站着吃  会撒出来
If I eat standing up, I spill.
我们儿子快死了  你怎么能无动于衷
Our son is dying, and you could care less.
我们遭受磨难  你却无所事事
We're going through hell. You're doing nothing?
对不起  你需要发泄  我理解
I'm sorry. You need to vent. I understand.
不用充好人
Don't be condescending.
你从来都没有去看过他
You haven't checked in on him once.
血压是110 70
Blood pressure is 110 over 70.
他的引流管放置于右侧脑室
His shunt is patent,
心电图显示正常QRS波群
The E.K.G. Shows a normal Q. R.S.
肢导和胸导T波倒置
With deep-wave inversions throughout both limb and precordial leads.
肝功能指标上升  但只高出一倍
L.F. T.'s are elevated, but only twice the normal range.
对了  他还幻听
Oh, yeah. And he's hearing voices.
去握着他的手
Go hold his hand.
去吧  我替你们还餐盘
Go on. I'll bus your tray.
你带取样袋了吗
Got any sample bags on you?
真搞不懂你
I don't believe you.
你要拿他们的DNA去比对吗
You're gonna run D.N.A. Tests?
他们儿子病得很严重
Their son is deathly ill.
我知道  这样不对
I know. It's terrible.
但如果我不注意这些小细节
But the fact is, if I don't keep busy with trivial things like this,
我都要愁哭了
I'm afraid I might start to cry.
你真是个混蛋
You're an ass.
是吗  赌注加倍好吗
Yeah? You want to double the bet?
"综合医院"在第六频道播出呢
General Hospital is on channel 6.
丹的脑部不会在第六频道显示出来
Dan's brain's not showing channel 6 right now.
只有一团乱
Only mush.
没有癫痫的症状
No epileptiform activity.
你在干吗
What are you doing?
等全血球计数和7项化学指标测试的结果
Waiting for C.B.C. And CHEM-7.
很好  将DNA做下比对
Good. Run D.N.A. On these.
这是什么
What's this?
他父母喝过的咖啡杯
Parents' coffee cups.
我搞不懂
I can't believe you.
这话我刚刚已经说过一遍了
I've had this conversation once already.
除非你有别的发现  不然照我的话做
If you've got something else to do, do it.  Otherwise, do this.
豪斯医生
Dr. House.
你好  福斯丁先生
Hey. Mr. Funsten.
刚在想你什么时候回来  这是给我的文件吗
I was wondering when you'd be back.  You got some papers for me?
你把我搞得郁闷死了
You've caused me considerable mental distress.
希望我有这能耐
I certainly hope so.
干嘛  是请不起律师呢
What? Too cheap to get your lawyer to serve it for you,
还是为了好玩  亲自拿来
or is it just more fun this way?
我已经想好解决办法了
I'm obviously prepared to consider a settlement.
你有淋病吧
You have gonorrhea.
我没有
No, I don't.
随你怎么说  化验结果显示你有
Well, maybe you're right, but I have the lab result says you do.
可能是假阳性  通常我会帮人做第二次检测
Could be a false positive,and normally I'd run a second test,
但既然你在这儿  我想就不用再检查了
but since you're here, I'll just go with the first.
你在吓唬我
You're just trying to scare me.
这是需要报告的  事关公众健康问题
It's reportable, you know. Public health issue.
我会告诉我妻子的
I'll be sure to let my wife know.
别那么麻烦  州里会帮你打电话的
Don't bother yourself.The state will call for you.
如果你是清白的  那就没事了  没什么大不了
If you're clean, I'm sure it'll all blow over. No big deal.
有个很简单的方法
There's an easy way to find out.
找个给你看过病的医生  检查一下
Get one of your doctors to run a test.
等等
Uh-uh.
现在  这是我的了
These are mine now.
法庭上见啦
I'll see you in court.
西尼罗河病毒检测室呈阴性  不奇怪啊
West Nile negative. Not surprising
泽西岛十二月份又没有很多蚊子
since not too many mosquitoes passing through Jersey in December.
东方型马脑炎也是阴性
No eastern encephalitis.
你们不会相信的
You guys aren't gonna believe this.
怎么啦
What's that?
豪斯是对的  他爸爸不是他的亲生父亲
House is right. The father's not the father.
他还把赌注加倍了
Dude doubled up on me.
你也不会相信
You're not gonna believe this.
他妈妈也不是他亲生母亲
The mother's not the mother either.
这种情况下  我们不建议您的孩子办理转院
It's not a good idea to move your son in his condition.
我们想听听别的医生的意见
We just want a second opinion.
我们想知道明确的结论
We need an answer.
你们这两个笨蛋  为什么骗我
You idiots.You lied to me.
我们没有隐瞒任何事
We didn't lie about anything.
反倒是你  指责我们骚扰自己的孩子
You, on the other hand, accused us of molesting our son.
你干的好事哈
Perfect.
能不能先别忙着说我  看看他们犯下的错误
Can we get off my screwups and focus on theirs?
他俩的错误更严重
Theirs is bigger
你们根本不是丹的父母
You're not Dan's parents.
我们是他的父母
We're his parents.
他是我们领养的  他不需要知道这点
He was adopted. He doesn't need to know.
我要知道
I do.
我们把他当亲生...
Adoption makes us just as much-
那我问你
Listen.
当被问到病史时  你们有没有一点疑惑呢
When we were taking his medical history, were you confused?
你不知道我们一直在基因方面找线索吗
Did you think we were looking for a genetic clue to his condition,
难道你们觉得  我会关心世上谁最爱他吗
or did you think we were trying to ascertain who loves him the most in the whole wide world?
你怎么发现的
How did you find out about this?
我取了他们的DNA化验
I sampled their D.N.A.
我们没给你
We didn't give you any D.N.A.
是自助餐厅的杯子上留下的
Your coffee cups from the cafeteria.
你不能这么做
You can't do that.
又来了  为什么要纠结我的行为
Again, why are we getting hung up on what I did?
你们的病史压根没用
Your medical history is useless.
不  我们提供的是他生母的详细资料
No. We gave you a detailed history of his biological mother.
她的资料  不吸烟  身体健康
Her history. Nonsmoker, good health,
低胆固醇  没有血压上的毛病
low cholesterol, no blood pressure problems.
在丹出生两周的时候  就被我们领养了
Dan was adopted two weeks after he was born.
你有他所有的资料  我们已经知无不言
You have his history. There's nothing you need to know that we didn't tell you.
很有道理
Sounds reasonable.
那么  如果你们想给他办转院  也可以
Well, if you want to transfer your boy, that is your choice.
但我还是觉得这不太好
I still think it's the wrong-
她打过疫苗吗
Was she vaccinated?
我是说他的生母  小时候打过疫苗吗
The biological mother. When she was a baby, did she get her vaccinations?
丹六个月大的时候  就打过疫苗
Dan was vaccinated. At six months.
是啊  那你知道为什么小孩
Mm-hmm. Do you know why kids
要在6个月时打疫苗呢
get vaccinated at six months?
因为在此之前  生母的免疫系统
Because before that they are protected...
能保护他们
by their biological mother's immune system.
所以  她打疫苗了吗
So, was she vaccinated?
婴儿染上麻疹病毒
An infant picks up a regular old measles virus.
会有皮疹
Gets a rash.
他会觉得很难受  发高烧
He's extremely uncomfortable, has a wicked fever,
但不会危及生命
but he lives.
但是有不定因素
Here's the kicker.
病毒突变的几率
Once every million or so times,
是百万分之一
the virus mutates.
丹没有发烧或皮疹
Instead of Dan having a fever and a rash,
是因为病毒潜入他的大脑中  隐藏起来
the virus travels to his brain and hides,
就像一颗定时炸弹
like a time bomb.
在这个病例中  它潜藏了16年
In this case, for 16 years.
亚急性硬化全脑炎
Subacute sclerosing panencephalitis.
我知道  在过去的30年里
I know. There's only been 20 cases in the United States
全国只发现过20例
in the last 30 years.
你是想说  这孩子还处于第一期吧
I suppose you could make an argument the kid's still in stage I.
一旦亚急性硬化全脑炎进入第二期
Once S.S.P.E. Moves to stage II, it's-
恶化速度加快  第二期通常是致命的
Boom. Stage II is universally fatal.
可谁都不知道  他什么时候会进入第二期
I assume its impossible to know when he might move into stage II.
他已经有第二期的一些症状了
He's already started showing symptoms.
可能是一个月后  也可能是今晚
Could be a month. Could be tonight.
-能治好吗  -问神经病学家吧
- Can we treat it? - Ask the neurologist.
脑室内注入干扰素
Intraventricular interferon.
没确诊前  又不能在脑袋上钻洞  注干扰素
Not gonna shove a spike into his brain and drip interferon without confirming this diagnosis.
抽脑脊液看看
Tap him.
我们无法从他的脑脊液中得到可靠的麻疹抗体
We won't get a reliable result for measles antibodies in his C.S.F.
在我们对他进行的这一系列治疗之后不行
Not after everything we've given him.
所以  错误的疗法毁了诊断正确的希望
So the wrong treatment kills any hope of the right diagnosis.
他们为什么要骗我呢
Why do people lie to me?
这可能会杀了他的
Could also kill him.
看你的了  福曼
Your ball, Foreman.
应该不用做大脑活组织切片检查吧
Tell me I don't have to biopsy his brain.
好吧  还有另一个方法
Well, there is one other way.
这个真的不疼吗
You sure this isn't gonna hurt?
当然  这只是有点可怕
Yeah. It's just scary as hell.
它会从你的瞳孔穿入
See, we go through the pupil.
你不会觉得疼  因为眼睛已经麻醉了
But you won't feel it. The eye's been paralyzed.
针会穿到你的眼睛后方
The needle travels to the back of the eye,
我们想在你的视网膜上  施行活组织检查
which is where we'll perform the biopsy on your retina.
已经确诊了  问题就出在这个变异的病毒上
So we've confirmed that the problem is this mutated virus.
治疗亚急性硬化脑炎是在脑室内注射干扰素
The treatment for S.S.P.E. Is intraventricular interferon.
我们会在头皮下植入奥马耶贮器
We implant an ommaya reservoir under the scalp,
与心室导管相连
which is connected to a ventricular catheter...
心室导管会将抗病原体直接输送至左脑
that delivers the antiviral directly to the left hemisphere.
你想让我同意手术吗
You want us to consent to this?
都不知道你在说什么
I don't even understand what you're talking about.
好吧  抗病原体...
Well, the antiviral-
好吧  对不起
Look. I'm sorry.
我会尽我所能跟您解释
I can explain this as best I can,
但要完全理解治疗过程
but the notion that you're gonna fully understand your son's treatment...
并作出决定  是...
and make an informed decision is-
是不可能的
is kind of insane.
你们要知道的是
Here's what you need to know.
治疗过程很危险
It's dangerous.
有可能致命
It could kill him.
但必须去做
You should do it.
还需要什么吗
Did you need something else?
你不能就为了打赌而花2300元去做DNA比对
You can't order a $3,200 D.N.A. Test to win a bet.
又不是实际成本
It's not an actual cost.
我不知道你是否清楚  但医院有DNA测序仪器
I don't know if you know this, but the hospital actually owns the sequencing machine.
我说真的
I'm serious.
那跟家长说  把账单寄给保险公司好了
Tell the parents to submit the bill to insurance.
保险公司才不会为了你们打赌付账呢
Insurance is not gonna pay for a bet.
会的  如果没有打赌  那孩子就死了
Should. We don't make that bet, the kid dies.
如果没有打赌  我就不会提取他们的DNA
If not for the paternity bet, I never would have taken their D.N.A.
这样  我们也不会发现丹是被领养的
Without their D.N.A., we never would have discovered that Dan was adopted,
这可是解决这个案子的关键
which was the key to this case.
你就是不想付赌债罢了
You just don't want to pay your end.
大错特错  我的人知道有个人...
Big mistake. My guy knows a guy.
好吧  我免去你一周的门诊
Fine. I will let you out of clinic duty for one week,
不过你要先付了基因扩增测试的3200元
after you pay the 3,200 for the P.C.R. Test.
好吧  这一百是你欠我的
Well, now, there's the hundred you owe me.
这一百是我从卡梅隆那里赢回来的
Here's a hundred I won from Cameron.
从福曼这里赢了两百
200 I took off of Foreman.
六百
And 600...
威尔森的
I got from Wilson.
真是苦涩啊
Very bitter.
早上好啊
Hey. Good morning.
脑电图显示正常  治疗有效果了
Good news on your E.E.G. Treatment is working.
免疫系统也有反应了
And your immune system is responding.
虽然早了点  还是让我看一下
I know it's early, but I just want to take a look.
好啦  现在看看脑子还灵不灵
All right.Let's see what that brain of yours can do.
"o"开头的动物  有多少说多少
Name as many animals as you canthat start with the letter "O."
鸵鸟
Ostrich.
公牛
Ox.
老象
Old elephant.
比上次好多了
Well, that's too better than last time.
关于领养的事  你还好吧
How you doing with the whole adoption thing?
我五年级的时候就知道了
I knew since fifth grade.
你怎么知道
How's that?
颏裂
Cleft chin.
我有  但是爸爸没有
I have one. My dad doesn't.
上网查了一下  颏裂是显性遗传
Looked it up on the Internet. It's one of those trait things.
是啊  常染色体显性遗传
That's right. It's autosomal dominant.
因为你的父母都没有颏裂
Since neither of your parents have cleft chins,
所以你很可能不是他们亲生的
it's highly unlikely you're biologically related.
你没事吧
Are you sure you're okay?
只是领养罢了  我没事
I've got no problems with being adopted.
我爱他们
I love my parents.
他怎么样了
How's he doing?
相当不错
He's doing pretty well.
他是个聪明的孩子
He's a smart kid.
他会好起来的
I think he's gonna be fine.
谢谢
Thanks.
背后球  18号  打背后
Wheels, 18. Wheels.